Joshua Taguicana

Web Developer



About

A new web developer dedicated to building creative websites and continue learning in new skills in a work environment. Previously worked in accounting, and gained organizational, timemanagement, and communication skills to creatively solve problems both individually and as a team.



Contact

joshtaguicana@gmail.com (627) 929-6216 Https://linkedin.com/in/joshuataguicana



Interests

- Music
- Guitar
- Piano
- Basketball
- Hockey
- Football
- Tennis
- Volleyball
- Snowboarding



Work Experience

Teaching Assistant BrainStation

June 2018 - Present

- Assist educators with the marking of assignments for current students as well as prep course entrance assignments for prospective students
- Set up and organized student files and folders for the new cohort and updated throughout the course
- Created daily challenges and white-boarding questions for students to assist with learning and understanding of the current weeks topic
- · Supported educators assisting with student questions during open studio

Fund Accountant CIBC Mellon

April 2018 - March 2019

- Ensured accuracy of a fund's trades, cash transactions, corporate actions, and verified correct pricing securities to properly calculate value of the fund portfolio
- Audited the work performed by other team members for the department to ensure accuracy and compliance with department and client instructions
- Calculated daily income accruals, expenses, interest, and dividend payments and ensured proper postings to the fund portfolio and analyzed daily changes in compliance with client exception tolerances
- Prepared daily and monthly distribution reports for clients as well as reinvestment calculations for distributions

Quality Assurance Agent Money Key

October 2016 - March 2018

- Audited the highest amount of loans firm wide through ensuring compliance with business and state regulatory policies by analysis of pay frequency, pay averages, and leverage resulting in higher quality lending due diligence
- Lead in training programs to assist new employees familiarize themselves with company processes
- Process debits and credits batches to meet the daily deadline. Audit batches for accuracy and confirm with bank
- Generated and analyzed trend reports for sales leads and customer service calls for management and supervisor review, identifying a need for stricter verification policies and customer education

Accountant Mnandi Pie, Acefoods Inc.

September 2016 - March 2018

- Performs full cycle bookkeeping and account reconciliation
- · Plans and assists with preparation of the company's budget and cash flow
- Provides financial reports and interprets information to manager while recommending further courses of actions
- Processes payroll, remittance and preparing T4 annually



Education

BrainStation Full-Time Web Development Diploma **Ryerson University** Bachelor of Commerce – Accounting

March 2019 August 2016

- Ryerson Orientation Crew: FROSH Week Leader
- · Ryerson Tax Clinic

Sheridan College Business Administration – Accounting

April 2013

- · Graduated with Honors
- First place group in Business Strategy Game



Skills

Ability to work individually or in a team and adapt to working styles of team members through proper communication. Developed knowledge in Microsoft Word, Excel, PowerPoint, QuickBooks, and Bloomberg, as well as HTML, CSS, JavaScript, React.js, and Node.js